Derek Martens

Telephone: 204-362-5341 Email: martensderek@gmail.com Website: www.martensderek.com

Professional Background

I am extremely organized and pay close attention to detail. I take initiative and look for ways to be as efficient as possible. I enjoy helping others. Coworkers and subordinates have called me dependable and reliable. I excel in leadership roles. I love working in teams and have experience in project and team management. I love working with others using our collective skills to create the best possible product.

Personal Skills

Organized, Attention to detail, Initiative, Efficient, Dependable, Problem Solving, Customer service, and Time Management.

Interpersonal Skills

Communication, Leadership, Team Management, and Project management.

Technological Skills

Programming Languages

Java, .NET Core, C#, Visual Basic, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3, Java, and JavaScript.

Frameworks

VueJS, NuxtJS, .Net, .Net Core

Software Development Tools and Practices

Git, Jira, Trello, and Agile development.

Academics

University of Manitoba | May 2020

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, Minor in Management

Concentrations in Software Engineering, Human-Computer Interaction, and Databases

Work Experience

Decor Cabinets

Software Developer

March 2021 - Current

With a small group of developers build a new dealer portal that integrates with the company's new ERP software. I also function as a **product manager**, where I am tasked with defining the user experience and all the required features.

Diamond Doors

Software Developer

September 2020 – October 2020

Contracted to create .Net Core and Visual Basic applications to integrate legacy Excel files with an existing database, as well as make recommendations on new technologies to help modernize the business.

University of Manitoba

Intramural Hockey Coordinator

September 2019 - April 2020

Manage of team of 11 employees to serve approximately 350 league participants. Responsibilities include scheduling games and employees, addressing client issues and complaints, as well as payroll and equipment management.

Intramural Hockey Referee

September 2017 – September 2019

Maintain a safe and enjoyable recreation experience for all players at all levels.

IDC Communications

Installation Compensation Coordinator / VBA Development

October 2018 – September 2019

Enter data into live spreadsheets, maintaining an extremely high level of accuracy. Find inefficiencies and implement Excel VBA solutions to increase productivity.

Sales Associate

November 2013 – October 2018

Offer quick and knowledgeable customer service, while maintaining sales targets and resolving various technical issues.